<article>
<fno>A1003</fno>
<doi>10.1041/A1003s-1995</doi>
<fm><hdr><hdr1><ti>IEEE Annals of the History of Computing</ti>
<crt><issn>1058-6180</issn>/95/$4.00 <cci><onm>1995 IEEE</onm></cci></crt></hdr1>
<hdr2><obi><volno>Vol. 17</volno>, <issno>No. 1</issno></obi>
<pdt><mo>Spring</mo><yr>1995</yr></pdt>
<pp>pp. 3-3</pp></hdr2></hdr>
<tig>
<atl>About this Issue</atl><pn>pp. 3-3</pn></tig>
<au sequence="first"><fnm>J.A.N.</fnm><snm>Lee</snm><role>Editor in Chief</role></au>
</fm>
<bdy>
<p>The first issue of our 17th volume is as diverse in topics as any nontheme issue that we have tried to present over the past many years. However, it still represents the work of the Englishspeaking world of the North Atlantic rather than a broader picture of computing in the whole world. The Editorial Board and the article editors of the <it>Annals</it>
are doing their best to bring the history of the whole world of computing to our readers, but it does require authors in other countries to offer their manuscripts for our consideration. Please take this as an open invitation to authors in other parts of the world to submit papers to the <it>Annals</it>
for review and help us to follow the lead of our parent organization in being the The Worlds Computer Society.</p>
<p>The five major articles in this issue represent several manuscripts that have been in our files for some time, and we are grateful to the authors for having stuck with us while we reviewed, rereviewed, and reworked their papers. Articles in the field of history do not always present the work of the authors themselves (though we welcome pioneers to give us their own stories, as in the case of the 1935 article by John McPherson in this issue); thus, answering the question is it accurate? is not always easy. In fact, we ask our referees to answer the following questions about each manuscript, and their responses determine whether we accept the manuscript as is or whether we ask the author(s) to revise the material:</p>
<l2>
<li>
<p>Are the issues addressed in the paper stated clearly enough?</p></li>
<li>
<p>What is right or wrong?</p></li>
<li>
<p>Are the facts correct?</p></li>
<li>
<p>Is documentation for facts and even opinions appropriate and sufficient? Are statements substantiated?</p></li>
<li>
<p>Are modern concepts being used inappropriately to interpret and/or evaluate earlier developments, i.e., is it a Whiggish approach?</p></li>
<li>
<p>Does the paper add to the public knowledge and/or literature of the subject?</p></li>
<li>
<p>Does the paper provide a balanced presentation regarding the environment in which the reported activity was initiated, the activity itself, and the resulting impact on the world?</p></li>
</l2>
</bdy></article>
